<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>zero-knowledge proofs on wborgeaud</title>
    <link>https://solvable.group/tags/zero-knowledge-proofs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in zero-knowledge proofs on wborgeaud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://solvable.group/tags/zero-knowledge-proofs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A simple multivariate AIR argument inspired by SuperSpartan</title>
      <link>https://solvable.group/posts/super-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://solvable.group/posts/super-air/</guid>
      <description>PDF version here and HackMD here.
We will consider the following basic version of AIR. Let $\mathbb{F}$ be a finite field and let $F \in \mathbb{F}[X_0,\dots,X_{2C-1}]$ be a constraint polynomial. An AIR witness for this instance is a table of $C$ columns $z_0,\dots,z_{C-1}$ of size $n=2^v$ such that for all $i=0,\dots,n-2$, $$ F(z_0[i],\dots,z_{C-1}[i],z_0[i+1],\dots,z_{C-1}[i+1])=0. $$
Multi-columns CCS (MCCCS) CCS is a constraint system introduced in [STW23]1 that generalizes common constraint systems such as R1CS, AIR, and Plonk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proving AIRs with multivariate sumchecks</title>
      <link>https://solvable.group/posts/air-multivariate-sumcheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://solvable.group/posts/air-multivariate-sumcheck/</guid>
      <description>Algebraic Intermediate Representation (AIR) is a powerful arithmetization that can be extended to Randomized Air with Preprocessing (RAP), which includes popular systems like PLONK. See this great note by Ariel Gabizon for descriptions of these arithmetizations.
Another popular arithmetization is given by R1CS. Two categories of proving systems based on R1CS are those using multivariate techniques (e.g. Spartan) and those using univariate techniques (e.g. Marlin).
To the best of my knowledge, every current AIR-based proving system uses univariate techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Membership proofs from polynomial commitments</title>
      <link>https://solvable.group/posts/membership-proofs-from-polynomial-commitments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 13:57:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://solvable.group/posts/membership-proofs-from-polynomial-commitments/</guid>
      <description>$$ \def\com{\mathbf{com}} $$
Recently, Dan Boneh, Ben Fisch, Ariel Gabizon, and Zac Williamson (BFGW) published a writeup showing how to create range proofs from polynomial commitments. As a mental exercise, I wanted to see how to use polynomial commitments to create membership proofs instead. Membership proofs can be seen as a generalization of range proofs, if certain homomorphic properties hold (that&amp;rsquo;s something I learned first from this article). For example for Pedersen commitments, we have:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
